B. V. SUDHAKAR

Email id: sudhakar.teachertrainer@gmail.com Phone: +91-6305326158



Career Objective

With my experience and knowledge, I would like to bring a major change in the education system by implementing innovative ideas and ideals. As an intelligent communicator, I would like to interact with lots of people, and work as a self-motivated person for planning organizational procedures and practices.

Professional Experience:

April 2019 – Present Program Success Manager ClassKlap Pvt. Ltd. Vijayawada

Responsible for ensuring seamless implementation of IMAX Program by driving implementation, collating feedback, and resolution to issues in coordination with the central team.

- Share the progress and escalate all issues concerning program implementation to the Program Success Central team.
- Mapping implementation gaps and providing constructive steps in coordination with the central team.
- Regular review of schools.
- Communication of the same with Central team, Training Managers and RM.
- Measure the effectiveness of the product in school and report it to the central team
- Collect feedback from all schools quarterly through visits.
- Collaborate with Training Managers on key schools' implementation.
- Escalate all issues concerning program implementation to the Program Success central team.
- Collaboration with Central team.
- Working with transparency in sharing feedback and proactively closing the issues.
- Active communication with all school correspondents and principals.
- Regular updates regarding the implementation and closure of issues.

March 2014 – October 2018 Executive official Trips International School Rajahmundry

- Executive official to manage day to day activities.
- Preparation of Daily Meeting Agendas in consultation with the Principal and Chairperson.
- Review, confirmation, and distribution of minutes of meeting.
- Set up and provide additional meetings as necessary from time to time.
- Provision of detailed monthly reports to the Board's Executive Committee.
- Prepare Operational Budgets in conjunction with the Principal and Senior Management for approval by the Board prior to breaking for holidays.
- Provision of regular monthly reports to budget holders.
- Management and reconciliation of College's activities.
- Social Studies teacher for primary section.
- Collect the student feedback about the faculty member's subject wise (for all the subjects taught to the students of their branch) and communicate the feedback to the concerned faculty members in the standard format as decided by principal.

June 2012-March 2014 Principal A.K.R.G. Degree College Rajahmundry

- General administration and overall supervision of teaching programmes.
- Supervision of student's welfare, health and security services.
- Supervision and guidance of teaching staff including organization of in-service education of staff.
- Responsibility for organizing workload of staff including teaching assignments.'

- Guidance and counselling of students.
- Administrative arrangements for students' clinical experience and teaching in hospital and public health field.
- · Recruitment of staff and admission of students.
- · Responsibility for conduct of examinations.
- Supervision of living conditions of students in hostel.

June 2010 – June 2012 HOD of M.C.A. A.K.R.G. College of P.G. COURSES Nallajerla, West Godavari.

- Allocate the subjects to the faculty members well in advance before commencement of the semester/year.
- Performing the duties of Teacher and Head a Department for a subject or group of subjects.
- Actively assisting the Head of School in ensuring the good professional practice, standards, and quality of teaching and learning of subject/s through proper dialogue with the class teachers and, under the direction of the relative Education Officer, promotes a healthy process of reciprocal informal observation of class teaching practices.
- Advising and contributing to curriculum development at school and system level under the direction and guidance of the respective Education Officer.
- Co-ordinating the teaching and learning of the subject/s for which one is responsible
- Collect lesson plans from teaching staff before the commencement of class work and ensure that the information provided is in accordance with the format.
- Interact with students (Section wise) of their branch 15 days once, identify the problems and find solutions in consultation with the principal.
- Observe the dress code among students and instruct the respective class advisors to implement the dress code among the students.
- Convene departmental staff meeting once in a week on the day allotted and record the minutes of the meeting.
- Communicate the attendance particulars and internal marks of students to the concerned parents from time to time with the help of class advisors.

June 2007 – June 2010 Asst. Professor (M.C.A) A.K.R.G. College of P.G. COURSES Nallajerla, West Godavari.

- Develop professional logistics to improvise student performance.
- Guide, lead, and mentor students in research projects.
- Evaluate, monitor, and mentor student academic progress.
- Create, innovate, and implement career-enhancement programs and activities.
- Supervise and support teaching assistants.
- Participate in departmental and college activities.
- Serve and support functional activities of departmental committees.
- Assess, review, and evaluate student activities and progress.
- Assist and support senior professors in their day-to-day tasks and functions.

June 2004 - May 2007 Trainer Pace Computer institute Ramachandrapuram

- Train and instruct students, learners and end-users in computer operations. Design and develop computer instructional material useful for end-users and learners.
- Brief and instruct end-users on new technologies, software programs and applications.
- Handle the learning and professional development of staff and equip them with the knowledge, practical skills and motivation to carry out work-related tasks.

June 2002 - April 2004 Lab demonstrator Aditya Degree College Kakinada

- Created whole lab sessions for the students. Responsibilities included the supervision of students in lab and practical implementations.
- Served as full time teacher responsible for implementing lesson plans and daily activities.

Certifications & Achievements:

- 1. **CEFR B2** in <u>English Proficiency</u> by British Council
- 2. **International Certified Career Coach** (Level 1) from *Career Development Alliance* by *Mindler*.

Publications:

1. A New Application of Data Mining

Bomma.Rama Krishna, Ch. Rama Devi, Anil Kumar D L V N S S S R, B V Sudhakar, Pantham Venkatesh

2. Network and Wireless Network Security

Pantham Venkatesh, B V Sudhakar, Anil Kumar D L V N S S S R, Bomma.Rama Krishna, Md. Shaffyvullah

Educational qualifications:

Degree	University & Place	Year	Percentage
M.C.A	Andhra University, Visakhapatnam	2007	73.23 %.
B.C.A.	Andhra University, Visakhapatnam	2004	76.9 %
Inter	Board of Intermediate Education, A.P	1999	65.5 %
S. S. C	Board of Secondary Education A.P, Hyderabad	1997	74.1%

Areas of Interest in Relevance:

M.C.A: C, C++, File Structures, AI, DBMS & Embedded systems.

B.C.A: C Programming, Computer networks, DBMS, Embedded systems, Hardware & networking.

Personal Details:

Name : B. V. SUDHAKAR Father's Name : B.V. Satyanarayana

Date of Birth : 22/06/1982 Marital Status : Married

Permanent Address : D. No: 5-47/1, Butchiah nagar, Rajahmundry, East

Godavari Dist., A.P. -533107.

E-mail : <u>sudhakar838@gmail.com</u>

Mobile No. : +91-6305326158

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the information mentioned above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date: (B.V. Sudhakar)